<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CVA4 – Blog</title>
    <link>https://cva4.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on CVA4</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://cva4.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Best Resume Formats for 2024</title>
      <link>https://cva4.com/blog/resume-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 21:54:37 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cva4.com/blog/resume-formats/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/best-resume-formats.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Resume Formats&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you format your resume &lt;strong&gt;matters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reviewing your resume, the first thing hiring managers notice is how your resume &lt;strong&gt;looks&lt;/strong&gt;, not what it &lt;strong&gt;contains&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if the first thing they see is a messy, cluttered, crowded resume, chances are you won’t make a great first impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this begs the question: what are the best resume formats, and which one should YOU use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resume Formatting Guidelines&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;resume-formatting-guidelines&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#resume-formatting-guidelines&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re formatting your resume from scratch, you’ll first want to pay attention to the layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That involves setting the margins, picking the font size, and determining your resume’s length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a professional-looking resume, follow these general formatting guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t make your resume longer than &lt;strong&gt;one page&lt;/strong&gt;. Unless you have 5+ years of relevant work experience, there’s no reason for your resume to be two or three pages long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick an &lt;strong&gt;11 or 12-pt font size&lt;/strong&gt; for normal text and 14-16pt for section titles and headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick an attention-grabbing (but professional) font. We recommend &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Roboto&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;Overpass&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use standard and legible resume sections. For example, your work experience should be called just that “Work Experience” and not “work history” or something else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage bullet points to list information such as work achievements and responsibilities, academic details, etc. They help make the resume much more reader-friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent with resume formatting (e.g. use the same date format everywhere, instead of using 11.2018 in one place and November 2018 in another).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have good line spacing. You don’t want the information on your resume to look all cramped up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always save your resume as a &lt;strong&gt;PDF file&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s the safest choice, as it guarantees your resume layout will stay intact no matter what device opens it. Only save your resume as MS Word if the job you’re applying for specifically requires you to and never, ever, submit a JPEG or PNG of your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resume Formats&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;resume-formats&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#resume-formats&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing you want to know is that there are four main resume formats out there, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reverse-&lt;strong&gt;chronological&lt;/strong&gt; resume format. This is the most common and practical resume format in 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;functional&lt;/strong&gt; resume format is also known as the &lt;code&gt;skills-based&lt;/code&gt; resume format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;combination&lt;/strong&gt; resume format, or hybrid resume format, is a combination of the other two formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;infographic&lt;/strong&gt; resume format, An infographic resume example uses &lt;code&gt;visual elements&lt;/code&gt; to highlight a candidate’s &lt;code&gt;creative&lt;/code&gt; qualifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’re probably asking yourself how these 4 formats are different from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the main difference is that they focus on different parts of an applicant’s experience by listing sections in different orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reverse-chronological resume format focuses on your &lt;strong&gt;work experience&lt;/strong&gt;, listing them from most to least recent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The functional resume format focuses on &lt;strong&gt;your skills&lt;/strong&gt; that are relevant to the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The combination resume format focuses on your &lt;strong&gt;experience and skills&lt;/strong&gt; by aiming to prove that you possess the skills you list through your work achievements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The infographic resume format focuses on your &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt; and presents it visually.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chronological Resume&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;chronological-resume&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#chronological-resume&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A chronological resume emphasizes your career progression by listing your experience in reverse-chronological order, starting with your most recent job listed at the top and each previous position in descending order. This is the most widely used resume format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing about this resume format is that it’s useful for practically every job-seeker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reverse-chronological format has a very simple structure, it’s easy to skim, and overall, it’s the most popular format around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason alone, we typically recommend using this format to most people  - even if using one of the other formats also makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It usually looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/svg/ChronologicalFormat_animated.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Chronological Resume&#34; style=&#34;height: 400px; width:300px;&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you’d include in a reverse-chronological resume:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Include&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-to-include&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-include&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Information&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;code&gt;Your name&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;phone number&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;email&lt;/code&gt; address. In some cases, you can include useful links such as a &lt;code&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;GitHub&lt;/code&gt; profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resume Summary or Objective&lt;/strong&gt; - A brief &lt;code&gt;2-4 sentence&lt;/code&gt; summary of your work experience, or your objective for applying for a given position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Title&lt;/strong&gt; - Your title. This should mirror the exact position you’re applying for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt; - Your work experience in reverse-chronological order. When possible, talk about achievements over responsibilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills Section&lt;/strong&gt; - Skills relevant to the position you’re applying for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt; - Your educational history. Pro tip - if you have a B.A., feel free to skip your high school education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional Sections&lt;/strong&gt; - Sections like volunteering, projects, portfolio, hobbies, etc. While they’re not a game-changer, they can help fill up some space on your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we already mentioned, this resume format primarily focuses on the one part that’s relevant to most hiring managers - your &lt;code&gt;work history&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, the key to making the most out of this resume format is nailing the work experience section. To do that, here’s how you should structure it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with your most recent job and go backward from there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailor the section to the job description. This means that you shouldn’t list every job you ever worked - only the ones that are relevant for this one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each job that you list, include your job title, the name of the company, the location, and the time period you worked there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Below, add four to five bullet points for recent jobs and two to three bullet points for earlier jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on your achievements instead of your responsibilities. Hiring managers already know the basic responsibilities of the jobs they’re hiring for. So, rather than your responsibilities, they want to learn about your achievements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever possible, quantify your achievements. Facts and numbers are more convincing than words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use action verbs and power words. (E.g. “created” instead of “was responsible for creating”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#example&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we already mentioned, the best thing about the reverse-chronological format is that it’s a great choice whether you’re an entry-level worker or a seasoned professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any relevant experience you’ve got, the chronological experience will highlight effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, here’s a digital marketer’s resume work experience section created using the reverse-chronological format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Marketing Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Wonderfull Agency Inc.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;06/2017 - Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a new format for reporting and presenting the sales, customer engagement and Google Ads reports that decreased the number of meetings by 24% in the last three quarters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated and monitored the Bid Strategy in Google Ads and Bing Ads which resulted in a CTR increase of 3.2% in the first month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redesigned the webpage UX, decreasing customer turnover by 25% within a period of two months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted keyword research for updating the product pages on the online shop, increasing the organic keywords in the Top 100 by 5.600 and in the Top 10 by 315 for high-volume searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Marketing Specialist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Company X&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;02/2015 - 05/2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborated with a copywriter and designer to update landing pages based on search intent, increasing conversion rates by 20% on average for select clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked directly with company clients, handling their Google Ads accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed a total of $40,000 in ad spend per month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieved an average of 200% ROAS overall ad accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pros &amp;amp; Cons&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;pros--cons&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#pros--cons&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still not sure if the reverse-chronological resume format is the right choice for you? See our pros and cons below!&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recruiters and HR managers prefer this format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will definitely “beat” Applicant Tracking System (ATS) software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides a reader-friendly chronological history of your work experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most popular resume format in 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to make your work achievements stand out to catch the recruiter’s attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard to fill in for a recent graduate with no work experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes career gaps very obvious. If you’re a career changer, you need to explain those employment gaps on your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Functional Resume&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;functional-resume&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#functional-resume&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Changing careers or have big gaps in your employment history? The functional resume format may be for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a lot of career gaps or &lt;strong&gt;don’t have much work experience&lt;/strong&gt;, you’ll benefit from using a resume format that focuses on your skills — and that’s exactly what the functional resume does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we already mentioned, the functional resume format is also known as the skills-based resume format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, the functional resume format focuses on your skills and your key strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, this resume format takes the spotlight away from your work experience by highlighting what you’re good at instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, this resume format is perfect for recent graduates or career changers who have little-to-no experience in a particular field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/svg/FunctionalFormat_animated.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Functional Resume&#34; style=&#34;height: 400px; width:300px;&#34;/&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Include&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-to-include-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-include-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resume Summary or Objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills Summary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work Experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the main difference from the reverse-chronological format is that the focus of the functional resume is the skills summary and the resume objective that’s placed right at the top of the resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is exactly how you should write them to impress the hiring manager:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your resume objective to state your career intent and explain what makes you the ideal candidate for the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start off your resume objective by mentioning a skill, education, or certification relevant to the job, mention the responsibilities you could handle, and include your motivation for working that particular job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the skills summary, include four or five skills that are most relevant to the position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of just listing your skills, be descriptive. In bullet points or in plain paragraphs, give examples of how you applied these skills in practice and try to make them as quantifiable as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;example-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#example-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume that you’re an entry-level journalist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you graduated, you’ve worked as a part-time intern at a magazine and published a dozen articles online and in print. You also run a blog that has a modest but loyal readership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you want to apply for an actual journalism position at a recently founded newspaper. So, you’re using the functional resume format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s why it’s the right choice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It highlights your skills&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, you don’t have the experience to apply for the job, but you may have all the right skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It allows you to prove your skills&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s ample space to show exactly how you can put your skills to use for the upcoming job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s see what your resume objective and skills summary (or areas of strength) would look like in this case:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resume Objective&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Driven and hardworking journalism graduate looking to get hired as a reporter in The Daily Prophet. I interned at Who Magazine for six months, where I gained hands-on experience in research, fact-checking, and interviewing. Passionate blogger at Fake Blog Website, which is currently followed by over two thousand readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Skills Summary&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research &amp;amp; Fact checking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to systematically look for information, resources, data, etc. through a variety of sources, such as books, online directories, or social media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Careful to always ensure that every claim and data that gets published is accurate and legitimate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full knowledge of journalism ethics and standards that are required to conduct successful and dignified interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skilled at connecting with interviewees on a deeper level to ensure comprehensive and detailed interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excel at several types of journalistic writing, including news, feature writing, columns, and reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have published over 15 articles in different newspapers and magazines since graduating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that the functional resume focuses solely on a candidate’s skills, the only groups of candidates who should consider using it are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freelancers with impressive portfolios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professionals in creative industries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Career changers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent graduates, and entry-level professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Military veterans passing into civilian roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pros &amp;amp; Cons&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;pros--cons-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#pros--cons-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, to sum it all up:&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good for highlighting specific skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful if you’re switching careers since you can explain how your skills transfer to the new job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful if you’re a recent graduate with practical skills but not much work experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The functional resume format is not very popular in 2024, and most recruiters and hiring managers aren’t familiar with it, so using this format carries a bit of a risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the functional resume has less focus on work experience, recruiters might think you’re trying to hide something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicant tracking systems (ATS) have difficulties reading functional resumes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;when-to-use&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#when-to-use&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should use a functional resume in the following situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to explain &lt;strong&gt;long periods of unemployment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re &lt;strong&gt;switching to a new career&lt;/strong&gt; and don’t have much relevant experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to &lt;strong&gt;highlight specific professional skills&lt;/strong&gt; rather than your experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By focusing on your skills, the functional resume emphasises the value you offer employers and draws attention away from your work history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Combination Resume&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;combination-resume&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#combination-resume&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The combination resume format, also known as the “hybrid,” is a mixture of the functional and the reverse-chronological format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combination resume format is especially well-suited for &lt;strong&gt;highly-trained job seekers&lt;/strong&gt; who want to place equal emphasis on their skills and work history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/svg/CombinationFormat_animated.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Combination Resume&#34; style=&#34;height: 400px; width:300px;&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resume format gives equal attention to an applicant’s skills section and work experience. As such, you end up including both the Skill Summary and the Work Experience sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skill Summary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work Experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focal point here is the skills summary. Placed right after the contact information section, this is where you list the skills that are required for the job and then prove that you have them through your professional experience and achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is exactly how you should write it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List the skills that are required for the position you’re applying for and that you actually possess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add up to 4 professional achievements underneath each skill to prove that you possess it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your achievements as descriptive and quantifiable as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;example-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#example-2&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say you’re a senior program manager with over a decade of experience in your field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can plan, execute, evaluate programs and projects across diverse industries, and inspire your team to do great work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, someone told you about an opening for a program director in an international company. To apply, you’re putting together a hybrid resume format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what makes it the best choice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saves space. For highly competitive positions, you want your resume to be able to cut through the noise. The hybrid format allows you to do that by bringing into focus your most relevant achievements right from the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combines the best parts of the other two resume formats, which is perfect for senior professionals or executives that have plenty to show for both experience and skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, some of the skills required for the program director gig mentioned above may include interpersonal skills, budget management, and project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what the skills summary in your hybrid resume would look like in practice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpersonal Skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initiated formal and informal coaching and mentorship to 50+ team members regarding project charter development, resource planning, best practices of project management, and appropriate delivery of project outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinated all project inputs with several functional/technical directors, managers, and project core teams, to formulate appropriate project tools and methodologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oversaw the implementation of the enterprise’s multi-year, multi-million dollar research system software that benefited employees company-wide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of financial and statistical data reduced operational costs by 12%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategically supervised the project execution teams to ensure the timely and cost-effective completion of projects, saving the company $250K in project costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided strategic direction, leadership, and project governance for a multimillion-dollar application project portfolio, which successfully supported a population of 60K+ end-users across the UAE and Saudi Arabia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamlined project management methodologies and communication in the IT division, which increased efficiency by 90%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accurately report on project status throughout its life cycle to 20+ project teams, stakeholders, and sponsors, encompassing budget estimation, scheduling, and resource planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pros &amp;amp; Cons&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;pros--cons-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#pros--cons-2&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;




  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows you to show off more of your experience and skills using less space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful for very senior professionals or executives who need to highlight more than just their work experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good for applicants who may have a noticeable employment gap but plenty of work experience nonetheless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As with the functional resume format, applicant tracking systems have difficulties reading combination resumes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re a recent graduate or don’t have much work experience, this resume format is not very useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As is the case with the functional resume, most hiring managers aren’t very familiar with this format, which might cause some confusion in the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;when-to-use-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#when-to-use-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should use a combination resume in the following situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re making a career change and want to emphasize your transferable skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have a specific, well-developed set of technical skills you want to highlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re a senior-level candidate with a diverse range of experience and skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Infographic Resume&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;infographic-resume&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#infographic-resume&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to make an infographic resume that helps you land your dream job? Use our examples, templates and expert tips below to get started in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job market is competitive, so it’s important to make your job application stand out any way you can. Using an infographic resume is one way to show off certain skills and set yourself apart from other applicants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, using an infographics resume isn’t for every job seeker. Before you try making an infographic resume, it’s important to consider whether it’s the right option for you and the job you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/svg/InfographicFormat_animated.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Infographic Resume&#34; style=&#34;height: 400px; width:300px;&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An infographic resume is a resume that uses graphics to visually represent information, often in the form of bar charts, graphs, timelines, or statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This style of visual resume is often used to convey a candidate’s skill in graphic design or another artistic field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An infographic resume is useful for grabbing attention and highlighting your skills in a creative way. However, in some cases using an infographic resume could come across as unprofessional and negatively impact your chances of landing a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s important to know when exactly it’s appropriate to use an infographic resume (and when it’s not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;when-to-use-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#when-to-use-2&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should only use an infographic resume when you’re using it to showcase skills directly related to the job you’re applying for (such as graphic design) and you’re capable of making it look professional. Generally, infographic resumes are only used if you’re applying for work in the arts or marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, here are some fields in which an infographic resume may strengthen your application:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphic design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content creation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brand management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of creative fields like these, however, using a graphic resume may wind up hurting your chances of landing a job by making you appear less professional or distracting from your work experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Verdict: What Is the Best Resume Format?&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-verdict-what-is-the-best-resume-format&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-verdict-what-is-the-best-resume-format&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered all 4 of the common resume formats, you’re probably wondering which one&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;best resume format out there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s our verdict:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 90%+ of the cases, we’d recommend going with a reverse-chronological resume format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2024, it’s the most common and useful format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicant tracking systems can read it without any problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All recruiters and hiring managers are familiar with this format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether you’re a recent graduate or a senior professional, it’s the easiest format to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, even if you’re a career changer, a highly-qualified professional, or a college student, it’s risky to choose one of the other two formats over the reverse-chronological one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a good chance that the applicant tracking system won’t be able to read your resume and automatically discard it - after all the time you put into creating the resume!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, recruiters might just not be familiar with these resume formats, or think that you’re just trying to hide the fact that you’re not experienced, and disqualify you based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the rule of thumb - when in doubt, go for the reverse-chronological resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written by: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrei-kurtuy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andrei Kurtuy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://novoresume.com/career-blog/resume-formats&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://novoresume.com/career-blog/resume-formats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://novoresume.com/career-blog/how-to-write-a-cv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to Write a CV (Curriculum Vitae) in 2024 [31+ Examples]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://novoresume.com/career-blog/functional-resume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to Write a Functional Resume [4 Free Templates Included]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://novoresume.com/career-blog/combination-resume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Combination Resume Guide [w/ Templates &amp;amp; Examples]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resumegenius.com/blog/resume-help/chronological-resume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chronological Resume Template, Examples, and Format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resumegenius.com/blog/resume-help/functional-resume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to Write a Functional Resume (with Template and Examples)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resumegenius.com/blog/resume-help/combination-resume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Combination Resume Template &amp;amp; Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resumegenius.com/blog/resume-help/infographic-resume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How to Make an Infographic Resume (with Examples and Templates)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Resume Builders for 2024: Top 12 Online Resume Builder Websites</title>
      <link>https://cva4.com/blog/one-page-resume-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 21:54:37 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cva4.com/blog/one-page-resume-templates/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that writing a resume can be time-consuming and difficult. That’s why I’ve taken the time to thoroughly test and evaluate the top online resume builders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a hiring manager with 6 years of experience who’s spent countless hours reviewing resumes, I know firsthand how challenging it can be to create a standout resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where online resume builders come in. They simplify the process, offering templates, pre-written content, and design options to help you create a professional-looking resume quickly. But with so many options out there, how do you know which one is worth your time and money?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help you make a more informed decision, I’ve reviewed the 12 best online resume builders for job seekers in 2024, rating them on the quality of their software, template options, pricing, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resume Genius&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;resume-genius&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#resume-genius&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Resume-Genius.avif&#34; alt=&#34;resumegenius.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Genius resume builder offers users 15 modern resume templates to choose from, all of which are highly professional and designed to be ATS-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what really sets us apart is our AI-powered resume software that adds pre-filled bullet points to your work experience section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each bullet point is pulled from a database of common professions, and highlights skills and responsibilities relevant to your career. The end result is that making your resume with our software is extremely fast and easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Resume Genius builder charges a one-time fee of &lt;code&gt;$2.95&lt;/code&gt; to download your custom-built resume, or a monthly fee of &lt;code&gt;$7.95&lt;/code&gt; for unlimited resumes and cover letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Indeed Resume Builder&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;indeed-resume-builder&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#indeed-resume-builder&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Indeed.avif&#34; alt=&#34;indeed.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Indeed is mostly known as a job board, it also provides one of the best free resume builders online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featuring eight unique templates, Indeed gives you everything you need to put together a strong resume. Additionally, its builder provides the option to add less common resume sections like military experience and patents, which makes it a good choice if you have nontraditional work experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed’s resume builder is straightforward and gets the job done. However, its templates are a bit basic and don’t do a great job of maximizing available space. I found myself wishing for additional features—like pre-written bullets and the ability to add skill bars—that other online resume builders provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re on a tight budget and need a simple, no-frills resume, Indeed’s builder is a solid choice. However, its template offerings aren’t exciting and its builder is missing some key features provided by other builders.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Costs nothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates are unimpressive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The builder lacks features found in other software options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Zety&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;zety&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#zety&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Zety.avif&#34; alt=&#34;zety.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest career advice websites on the internet, Zety provides a helpful paid resume builder with plenty of template options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zety’s resume builder offers an extensive library of pre-written bullet points, skills, and resume summaries, making it one of the more helpful builders I tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found it incredibly time-saving. Zety’s industry-specific bullet points and resume summaries are genuinely helpful. The fill-in-the-blank templates for each section made the writing process a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main critique of Zety is that the templates are a tad too similar in style for my liking. While they’re great for creating a modern, minimalist resume, you might struggle to stand out if you’re looking for something more unique. Still, for efficiency and helpful content, Zety is hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zety’s resume builder costs $1.95 for a 14-day trial, after which they charge $25.95 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: Zety’s resume builder is beginner-friendly and convenient to use. However, their templates all feature a very similar style.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convenient and fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helpful pre-written content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates all use the same style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Canva Resume Builder&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;canva-resume-builder&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#canva-resume-builder&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Canva.avif&#34; alt=&#34;canva.com/create/resumes&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canva offers the best free resume builder, with a wide range of templates and customization options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canva’s free builder is a designer’s dream, boasting an unmatched variety of templates. I was honestly blown away by the sheer number of options – it’s perfect if you want your resume to have a distinct visual flair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But be warned: you’ll need to manually input all your info. Unlike some other online resume builders, Canva doesn’t offer pre-filled text or provide advice on how to write your resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can’t upload your current resume for a redesign, and will have to fill in each text field individually. This makes it a more time-consuming option than other websites I tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canva’s resume builder is free to use, but many features and templates require you to sign up for a Canva Pro account, which is $120 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: With a huge library of templates, Canva is the best free resume builder online, and is a great choice for graphic designers in particular. However, if you’re short on time or aren’t sure what to include on your resume, you’re better off using a more streamlined, content-focused resume builder.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many resume template options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly customizable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to manually fill in each section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little resume writing guidance offered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;LiveCareer&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;livecareer&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#livecareer&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/LiveCareer.avif&#34; alt=&#34;livecareer.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LiveCareer has provided expert advice and resume building services for over 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LiveCareer’s resume builder is fast, intuitive, and provides a wide variety of professional-looking templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love that you can import existing resumes – it’s a real time-saver if you’re just looking to refresh your current CV. The builder is fast and user-friendly, clearly refined over years in the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only gripe? The templates look outdated. They’re functional, but lack the modern edge you might want for creative or tech-focused roles. That said, for traditional industries, these templates might be just what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LiveCareer’s resume builder provides unlimited 14-day access for $2.95 or $5.95 for a monthly subscription, making it a cheaper option. However, it doesn’t offer a free trial period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: LiveCareer’s resume builder is quick, affordable, and easy-to-use. It’s a great option for the average job seeker. However, their templates are due for an update.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous template options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, easy-to-use builder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates look outdated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Resume Companion&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;resume-companion&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#resume-companion&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Resume-Companion.avif&#34; alt=&#34;resumecompanion.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although relatively small when compared to the other sites on this list, Resume Companion provides a high-quality resume maker that’s just as good (if not better) than most of the other options online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resume Companion’s builder impressed me with its modern, colorful templates—perfect for younger job seekers or those in creative fields. I particularly loved the pastel color options, which add a touch of personality without being unprofessional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their builder is user-friendly and straightforward, though it lacks some advanced features found in competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Resume Companion resume builder charges a $2.95 trial fee, or a monthly fee of $7.95 for full access to their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re after a fresh, contemporary look and don’t need tons of bells and whistles, Resume Companion is worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great resume templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beginner-friendly builder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lacks some features offered by other builders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Novorésumé&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;novorésumé&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#novor%c3%a9sum%c3%a9&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Novoresume.avif&#34; alt=&#34;novoresume.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Denmark, Novoresume provides a modern resume builder that works well for job seekers on either side of the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I appreciated that Novoresume’s builder allows you to adjust fonts, margins, and layouts—it’s great if you like to fine-tune every detail. The built-in tips were also genuinely useful, especially for less experienced job seekers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Novo’s templates are quite similar, and some features (like encouraging users to add a profile picture to their resume) aren’t ideal for US/UK job seekers. It’s clearly more geared towards European markets, which could be confusing for some users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, if you want a highly customizable experience and don’t mind a learning curve, Novoresume is a good option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Novoresume builder uses a freemium model, so you can download your resume as a PDF for free. However, if you want extra features, you’ll need to pay $19.99 per month or $39.99 for three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: Novoresume offers a good free resume builder. Their software is powerful and has some unique features. However, their templates are all quite similar and their builder seems geared more toward European job seekers.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helpful writing tips inside the builder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free to try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might be confusing for U.K. or U.S. users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Template offerings are very similar looking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premium access is expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;ResumeNerd&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;resumenerd&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#resumenerd&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/ResumeNerd.avif&#34; alt=&#34;resumenerd.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ResumeNerd’s builder is a godsend for beginners, offering tons of pre-written examples and tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was impressed by how thoroughly it guided me through each section — it’s like having a career coach by your side. The tips before each section are also genuinely helpful and insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But their templates? Not the most impressive or space-efficient I’ve seen. If you have a lot of experience to showcase, you might find yourself struggling to fit everything in. It’s an excellent choice for entry-level job seekers or those creating their first resume, but experienced professionals might find it limiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ResumeNerd’s paid resume builder costs $2.75 for a 14 day trial, and a $23.75 per month subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: ResumeNerd’s builder is very easy to use and provides a range of tips and pre-written content, making it a great option for entry level job seekers. However, their template options aren’t as impressive as those offered by competitors.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beginner-friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-written content helps with writer’s block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic template options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;EnhanCV&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;enhancv&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#enhancv&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/Enhancv.avif&#34; alt=&#34;enhancv.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EnhanCV offers one of the best free resume builders online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When starting EnhanCV’s resume builder process, you’re greeted by Julia, a virtual assistant and “resume expert”. While a bit gimmicky, the overall aesthetic is very modern and cutting-edge, which I loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, unlike some other resume builders, EnhanCV doesn’t offer a guided experience or pre-written options to speed the resume writing process along. Not having these elements makes EnhanCV’s service a bit intimidating for anyone without experience writing a resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also on the pricier side, which might be a deterrent for some. EnhanCV provides a freemium service, so you’re able to download a basic resume from their builder without paying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, to access their full library of templates, designs, fonts, and colors, you’ll need to pay $24.99 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: EnhanCV’s resume builder is sleek and modern, but doesn’t offer a lot of help for beginners. Additionally, their premium service is costly compared to other online resume builders.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modern resume template designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polished experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not beginner-friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full access is pricey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;MyPerfectResume&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;myperfectresume&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#myperfectresume&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/MyPerfectResume.avif&#34; alt=&#34;myperfectresume.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JobScan’s resume builder is straightforward and formats information well, even if you don’t have much work experience to list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where JobScan excels is its ATS-compatibility check. Once you’ve generated your resume, you’re offered a free scan to determine what information you’re missing, if you need to add keywords, and how your skills stack up against the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside? Very limited template options. The designs are basic and not particularly eye-catching. But if your primary concern is getting past ATS systems at large companies, JobScan is definitely worth considering. Just be prepared to sacrifice a bit on the visual appeal front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JobScan’s resume builder is free. But if you want extra features and more in-depth resume scans, you need to pay $49.95 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: JobScan offers one of the best free resume builders online, with a focus on getting you through ATS scans. However, their template offerings are very limited and their builder lacks some of the features available in other builders.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates are tailored for different experience-levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helpful pre-written content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many templates are old-fashioned or are poorly formatted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;JobScan&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;jobscan&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#jobscan&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/jobscan-resume-builder.webp&#34; alt=&#34;jobscan.co&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JobScan’s resume builder is straightforward and formats information well, even if you don’t have much work experience to list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where JobScan excels is its ATS-compatibility check. Once you’ve generated your resume, you’re offered a free scan to determine what information you’re missing, if you need to add keywords, and how your skills stack up against the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside? Very limited template options. The designs are basic and not particularly eye-catching. But if your primary concern is getting past ATS systems at large companies, JobScan is definitely worth considering. Just be prepared to sacrifice a bit on the visual appeal front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JobScan’s resume builder is free. But if you want extra features and more in-depth resume scans, you need to pay $49.95 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: JobScan offers one of the best free resume builders online, with a focus on getting you through ATS scans. However, their template offerings are very limited and their builder lacks some of the features available in other builders.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Includes an ATS scan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very basic templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Few features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Resume.io&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;resumeio&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#resumeio&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cva4.com/images/2024/resumeio-builder.avif&#34; alt=&#34;resume.io&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resume.io’s sleek platform immediately caught my eye with its polished interface and user-friendly design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standout feature here is the live preview – being able to see changes in real-time is a game-changer. Their editor is also top-notch and refreshingly problem-free compared to some other builders I’ve wrestled with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it’s not without its drawbacks. Being forced to sign up before you can start creating is mildly annoying. Plus, the limited customization options and small template selection left me wanting more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pricing is tiered, with a 7-day trial for $2.95 that auto-enrolls into a $24.95/month subscription if you don’t cancel. They also offer 6-month and 12-month packages at $44.95 and $74.95 respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict&lt;/strong&gt;: Resume.io is a solid choice if you prioritize a smooth user experience and don’t need extensive customization. That real-time preview feature is truly impressive. But if you’re after variety and deep customization options, you might want to keep looking.&lt;/p&gt;





  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-blue-200 hx-bg-blue-100 hx-text-blue-900 dark:hx-border-blue-200/30 dark:hx-bg-blue-900/30 dark:hx-text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ℹ️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleek and professional interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live preview feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;






  












&lt;div class=&#34;hx-overflow-x-auto hx-mt-6 hx-flex hx-rounded-lg hx-border hx-py-2 ltr:hx-pr-4 rtl:hx-pl-4 contrast-more:hx-border-current contrast-more:dark:hx-border-current hx-border-yellow-100 hx-bg-yellow-50 hx-text-yellow-900 dark:hx-border-yellow-200/30 dark:hx-bg-yellow-700/30 dark:hx-text-yellow-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;ltr:hx-pl-3 ltr:hx-pr-2 rtl:hx-pr-3 rtl:hx-pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx-select-none hx-text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;
        ⚠️
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx-w-full hx-min-w-0 hx-leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx-mt-6 hx-leading-7 first:hx-mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forced signup before starting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited customization options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Frequently asked questions about resume builder websites&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;frequently-asked-questions-about-resume-builder-websites&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#frequently-asked-questions-about-resume-builder-websites&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of answers to questions we frequently receive about resume builder websites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do employers think of resume builder platforms?&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-do-employers-think-of-resume-builder-platforms&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-do-employers-think-of-resume-builder-platforms&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s what employers think of resume builder platforms: they care about the content of your resume, not how you made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you wrote your resume from scratch, used a resume template, or created it using a resume builder platform, employers are focused on your resume’s content. To give yourself the best chance of getting called in for an interview, ensure you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantify the achievements on your resume with hard numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use action verbs to make yourself seem proactive and flexible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include keywords from the job ad in your resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is the best free resume maker?&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-the-best-free-resume-maker&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-best-free-resume-maker&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best free resume maker is any resume builder that allows you to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a professional, pre-formatted template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your personal information (name, email address, and phone number) and automatically fit those details into your template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick pre-written, error-free bullet points for jobs in your field, and format them for you in your work experience section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any good resume maker should offer these features and more, and help you write a resume in about 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written by: &lt;a href=&#34;https://resumegenius.com/author/conrad&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Conrad Benz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://resumegenius.com/blog/resume-help/best-resume-builder-website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://resumegenius.com/blog/resume-help/best-resume-builder-website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
